<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cam Pedersen</title>
    <description></description>
    <link>http://campedersen.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://campedersen.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>Adventures</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I was feeling bored a few months ago, and that’s usually no good. I tend to take things apart and not be able to put them back together when I’m bored. Or just break stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/pow.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had been perfectly content with life before I went to Asia. It wasn’t even a big trip - a week in Tokyo to acclimate and a week in Kuala Lumpur to speak at &lt;a href=&quot;http://conference.hitb.org/hitbsecconf2014kul/&quot;&gt;Hack In The Box&lt;/a&gt; with colleague and friend &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/deezthugs&quot;&gt;David Dahl&lt;/a&gt; about &lt;a href=&quot;https://crypton.io/crypton.pdf&quot;&gt;Crypton&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m no stranger to domestic travel - if somebody wants to go on a roadtrip, I’ll probably be the first to throw my shit in the back of a car. I’ve driven around the states a few times - most recently with my dad to check out the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rainbow_Gathering&quot;&gt;Rainbow Gathering&lt;/a&gt; and previously with my little sister and a couple of friends for a healthy dose of Americana.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://vine.co/v/blMDtxhgFeV/embed/simple&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;600&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, it was also my first time out of the US, and I didn’t know how mind-bending being in not-America would be for me. The mind-bending parts weren’t the language barrier and culture shock, but the perniciously tiny details that I would have never thought about. Like that the doors would be different sizes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/door.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I couldn’t experience enough weird doors and pernicious details. I think people call it the “travel bug”. As a programmer, I think that’s apt - it’s definitely not optimal behavior for a well-functioning human.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/cam-in-japan.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided to extend my trip by a week and travel solo to Thailand. This also happened to be my first time having access to $0.50 beers, so I don’t have many stories from that week other than sitting drunk on a beach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I reached an important conclusion on that beach though, after fending off packs of 8-year-olds trying to sell me necklaces: I wanted more experiences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This isn’t really a profound conclusion. Plenty of people have thought it and I’m just another random sack of flesh. A violent serving of Thai curry laughed at my philosophical thoughts and I decided to fly home after I could leave the bathroom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Home was comfortable, but it lacked monkeys and beaches. In Universal timing, Minnesota winter had begun and tried to keep me in the house with pent-up energy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://vine.co/v/OpvQZx6nALH/embed/simple&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;600&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The travel bug was stuck in the back of my head like bed bugs in a New York apartment. So I decided to make my “new year’s resolution” to take more adventures. It started with a last minute trip to New York for New Year’s Eve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://vine.co/v/Od7DX65um9L/embed/simple&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;600&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It felt good to make deciscions like that. I had a ton of fun, caught up with old friends, and made some new ones. I skipped the Times Square thing. Fuck that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/nyc.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided to keep the adventure going. I got an interview out in San Francisco and decided it would make a fine continuation. I flew home to Minneapolis for a night to do laundry, and out to California the next day. I had been to San Francisco a dozen times before, but it has a funny way of making you fall in love with it. Maybe it was the juxtaposition of climates in January.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/golden-gate-park.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Through another act of Universal timing, I got the job. It seemed it was roadtrip time again. My mom was worried about something indeterminate like moms tend to be, and my dad made me promise not to start wearing lycra.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was hard to say goodbye to my friends, but we went on a couple of micro-adventures before I left.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://vine.co/v/OpP9mZAvtI2/embed/simple&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;600&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://vine.co/v/OjFjQV3Jal9/embed/simple&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;600&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I packed up the shit in my studio and loaded up my car with some help from my friends. Trying to be pragmatic about driving over the Rockies in the middle of winter, I decided that a trailer was a bad idea and I had to sell my motorcycle. I gave it to Brian for $300 or a bitcoin, I don’t really remember. I couldn’t ride for shit, but I miss that bike. Here’s a video showing me getting distracted by girls in the street and missing first gear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/IaTKsfj6Cyk&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I ended up leaving at night which was pretty dumb in retrospect. After I got through the 4-foot snow drifts on southwestern Minnesota highways, it was a pretty smooth drive. I made a pitstop to see some weird-looking rocks. Rushmore is dead in the middle of winter, and the employees seemed happy to see someone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/rushmore.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I dropped in to see my brother and his family in Salt Lake, drove through the salt flats, then spent a night in Reno. Nobody had told me they give you free drinks in Reno as long as you’re at a table gambling. Fortunately I’m pretty good at blackjack - it was a profitable night and a painful morning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/salty-water.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After paying the bay area bridge toll trolls $5, I reached the coast. That was a pretty good feeling too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I arrived a week before I started my job to find a place to live. I heard apartment hunting in San Francisco was terrible. It was very terrible. I stayed in the cheapest hotel I could find for a week and started craigslisting fulltime. I got a few responses after 12 hours of sending emails.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the places I checked out advertised itself as a “communal living situation” which seemed like a nice way to meet people. It was more like a tenement city when I showed up, and the experience was just bizzarre - $1500 per month for a bunk bed in a closet and a shared bathroom. One of the current tenants sneakily told me to google the place before I sign a lease, and I’m glad I did. I nexted that place quick.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I finally found an apartment that wouldn’t make me broke, and somehow got it even though there were other people at the open house. I got really lucky. The shower is a weird shape though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/shower.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Street parking in San Francisco is a shitshow. The law says you can’t park anywhere for more than 3 days, and each street has a different street cleaning schedule. I sold my car after moving it around twice a week for a month. I got a bike and it’s a lot more fun!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/bike.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I’m settled in for now. My job is challenging and awesome, I’ve met some great people in the last month, and I think I’d maybe like to grow some roots here. I’m still thinking about my next adventure though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script src=&quot;https://platform.vine.co/static/scripts/embed.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2015 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://campedersen.com/2015/03/01/adventures/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://campedersen.com/2015/03/01/adventures/</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>

